Morton Gould Papers
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1920-1995 (Box 1-104, 146)
  - Arrangements
    - Waltz (Brahms, op. 39, no. 15), Score (Box-folder 68/2)
    - Waltz rhapsody, Score, parts (Box-folder 68/3)
    - The way you look tonight, Score, parts (Box-folder 68/4)
    - We'll have a new home in the morning, Score, parts (Box-folder 68/5)
    - Were you there when they crucified my Lord and Steal Away (strings), 1961, Score (Box-folder 69/1)
    - West wind (voice, orchestra), Score, parts; Laid in: sheet music used for arrangement (Box-folder 69/2)
    - What is there to say, Scores, parts (Box-folder 69/3)
    - What's new, Score, parts (Box-folder 101/4)
    - What's the name of that song: popular melodies (voice, orchestra), Score, parts (Box-folder 69/4)
    - When Yuba plays the rumba on the tuba, Score, parts (Box-folder 69/5)
    - When winter comes, Score, parts (Box-folder 102/1)
    - Why do I love you (harp, strings), Scores (Box-folder 69/6)
    - Why dream, Score; Laid in: sheet music used for arrangement (Box-folder 69/7)
    - Will love find a way (voice, orchestra), Score, parts; Laid in: sheet music used for arrangement (Box-folder 69/8)
    - The world is in my arms, Score, parts (Box-folder 102/2)
    - Ya got me, Score, parts (Box-folder 102/3)
    - Yankee Doodle (band), Parts; Laid in: letter from publisher to Gould (Box-folder 70/1)
    - Yankee Doodle, Score, parts, sketches (Box-folder 70/2)
    - Yellow bird, Score; Laid in: orchestral seating arrangement (Box-folder 70/3)
    - You and the night and the music, Parts; Laid in: sheet music used for arrangement (Box-folder 70/4)
    - You have taken my heart, Score, parts (Box-folder 71/1)
    - You let me down, Score, 2 parts (Box-folder 71/2)
    - You walked out of the picture, Score, parts; Laid in: sheet music used for arrangement (Box-folder 71/3)
    - You're laughing at me (voice, orchestra), Score, parts; Laid in: sheet music used for arrangement (Box-folder 71/4)
  - Music by Other Composers
    Principally manuscript copies in Gould's hand and arrangements of Gould works in the hands of others.
    - Bach goes to town (Templeton; arrangement by von Hallberg) (orchestra), Parts (Box-folder 71/5)
    - Broadway rhythm (arrangement by Lang) (voice, orchestra), Scores (Box-folder 71/6)
    - Can't we be friends (Swift and James; arrangement by Gifford) (orchestra), Score, parts (Box-folder 71/7)
    - Columbia (Gould; arrangement by Brunell) (band), Scores (Box-folder 92/1)
    - Eight fanfares for two trumpets (LaFave), 1993, Score; Written in commemoration of Gould's 80th birthday (Box-folder 104/16)
    - Festive music (Gould; transcription by Jirousek) (band), Score; Laid in: correspondence (Box-folder 92/2)
    - Fiesta (Samuels and Whitcup; arrangement by Skinner) (orchestra), Score, parts (Box-folder 71/8)
    - Guantanamera (Espigul) (chorus, piano), Score (Box-folder 72/1)
    - Hiccups: a rag (Paget) (orchestra), 1989, Score (Box-folder 104/17)
    - In a pagoda and The teddy bears picnic (Bratton; arrangement by Salcer) (piano, orchestra), Scores; Laid in: correspondence (Box-folder 72/2)
    - Isn't this a lovely day (Berlin; arrangement by Skinner) (orchestra), Score, parts (Box-folder 72/3)
    - Ivan Clyde (Grayson) (unspecified instruments), Sketch (Box-folder 72/4)
    - Jazz trilogy (Lawrence) (jazz combo, orchestra), Score; Laid in: correspondence, photographs, clippings (Box-folder 72/5)
    - Kingdom coming and The girl I left behind me (Worth), Sketches (Box-folder 104/18)
    - Lamento gitano (Grever; arrangement by Samuels, Whitcup and Powell) (orchestra), Parts (Box-folder 72/6)
    - March: E. F. G. (Leidzein), circa 1933?, Part; Written for Edwin Franko Goldman appearance in New York City (Box-folder 104/19)
    - Soft shoe serenade (arrangement by Caravas) (band), 1957, Score (Box-folder 72/7)
- Correspondence, 1929-1996 (Box 105-110)
  - 1929-1970 (Box-folder 105/1-5)
  - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 106/1-6)
  - 1973-1986 (Box-folder 107/1-7)
  - 1987-1991 (Box-folder 108/1-6)
  - 1992-1995 (Box-folder 109/1-4)
  - Undated (Box-folder 109/5-6)
  - Arlen, Harold, 1943 (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Bazelon, Irwin, 1994 (Box-folder 110/2)
  - Benny, Jack, 1970 (Box-folder 110/3)
  - Bergman, Alan, undated (Box-folder 110/4)
  - Berlin, Irving, 1988 (Box-folder 110/5)
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1970, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 110/6)
  - Biden, Joseph, 1987 (Box-folder 110/7)
  - Bloch, Ernest, 1927, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 110/8)
  - Cahn, Sammy, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 110/9)
  - Clinton, William Jefferson, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 110/10)
  - Comissiona, Sergiu, 1983, 1995 (Box-folder 110/11)
  - Corigliano, John, 1993 (Box-folder 110/12)
  - Cunningham, Merce, 1992 (Box-folder 110/13)
  - D'Amboise, Jacques, 1991 (Box-folder 110/14)
  - DeMille, Agnes, 1969-1970, 1988 (Box-folder 110/15)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1957 (Box-folder 110/16)
  - Fennell, Frederick, 1969 (Box-folder 110/17)
  - Fiedler, Arthur, 1941, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 110/18)
  - Frank, Barney, 1987 (Box-folder 110/19)
  - Gershwin, George, 1937, Letter from Gerswhin to Eva Gautier about Gould (Box-folder 110/20)
  - Golschmann, Vladimir, 1943, 1955 (Box-folder 110/21)
  - Goossens, Eugene, undated (Box-folder 110/22)
  - Gore, Albert, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 110/23)
  - Grainger, Percy, 1944-1961 (Box-folder 110/24)
  - Grofé, Ferde, 1966 (Box-folder 110/25)
  - Hatch, Orrin, 1993 (Box-folder 110/26)
  - Heifetz, Jascha, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 110/27)
  - Henderson, Skitch, 1980 (Box-folder 110/28)
  - Humphrey, Hubert, 1967 (Box-folder 110/29)
  - Ives, Charles, undated (Box-folder 110/30)
  - Kennedy, Edward, 1994 (Box-folder 110/31)
  - Kern, Jerome, 1944 (Box-folder 110/32)
  - Koch, Edward, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 110/33)
  - Kostelanetz, Andre, 1979 (Box-folder 110/34)
  - Koussevitzky, Serge, 1943 (Box-folder 110/35)
  - Laderman, Ezra, 1961, 1986 (Box-folder 110/36)
  - Larsen, Libby, 1995 (Box-folder 110/37)
  - Maazel, Lorin, 1981, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 110/38)
  - Mancini, Henry, 1986, 1994 (Box-folder 110/39)
  - Martin, Mary, 1983 (Box-folder 110/40)
  - McMahon, Ed, undated (Box-folder 110/41)
  - Mehta, Zubin, 1971 (Box-folder 110/42)
  - Mitropoulous, Dmitri, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 110/43)
  - Moses, Robert, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 110/44)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1957 (Box-folder 110/45)
  - Ormandy, Eugene, 1983 (Box-folder 110/46)
  - Perlman, Itzhak, 1985 (Box-folder 110/47)
  - Previn, Andre, 1970, 1995 (Box-folder 110/48)
  - Prince, Harold, 1995 (Box-folder 110/49)
  - Quill, Shirley, 1951, 1978-1992 (Box-folder 110/50)
  - Rapée, Ernö, 1943 (Box-folder 110/51)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 110/52)
  - Reed, Alfred, 1987 (Box-folder 110/53)
  - Reiner, Fritz, 1938-1945, 1957 (Box-folder 110/54)
  - Revelli, William, 1945, 1971, 1983 (Box-folder 110/55)
  - Robbins, Jerome, 1982-1996 (Box-folder 110/56)
  - Rockefeller, Jr., David, 1972 (Box-folder 110/57)
  - Rodgers, Richard and Oscar Hammerstein II, undated, Party invitation (Box-folder 110/58)
  - Rodzinski, Artur, 1943-1947 (Box-folder 110/59)
  - Rorem, Ned, 1988, 1995 (Box-folder 110/60)
  - Rostropovich, Mstislav, 1984-1995 (Box-folder 110/61)
  - Schuller, Gunther, 1979 (Box-folder 110/62)
  - Schuman, William, 1972, 1984 (Box-folder 110/63)
  - Shaw, Robert, 1969 (Box-folder 110/64)
  - Siegmeister, Elie, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 110/65)
  - Simon, Paul [Senator], 1995 (Box-folder 110/66)
  - Sinatra, Frank, 1994 (Box-folder 110/67)
  - Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1947, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 110/68)
  - Solti, Georg, 1971, 1987 (Box-folder 110/69)
  - Sondheim, Stephen, 1994 (Box-folder 110/70)
  - Steinway, Henry Z., 1969, 1993 (Box-folder 110/71)
  - Steinway, Theodore, 1953 (Box-folder 110/72)
  - Stevens, Risë, 1993 (Box-folder 110/73)
  - Stokowski, Leopold, 1935-1956, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 110/74)
  - Susskind, Walter, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 110/75)
  - Swift, Kay, 1986 (Box-folder 110/76)
  - Szell, George, 1947 (Box-folder 110/77)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1988 (Box-folder 110/78)
  - Toscanini, Arturo, 1942, 1950 (Box-folder 110/79)
  - Williams, John, 1991 (Box-folder 110/80)
  - Willson, Meredith, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 110/81)
  - Zaimont, Judith, 1994 (Box-folder 110/82)
- Business Papers, 1941-1995 (Box 111-116)
  - General Files, 1941-1995
    - ABA-JBA Convention, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 111/1)
    - AFM Congress of Strings, 1971, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 111/2)
    - American Symphony Orchestra League, 1967-1971, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 111/3-4)
    - ASCAP, 1981-1994, undated (Box-folder 111/5-7)
    - Birthday celebrations. 70th, 1983 (Box-folder 112/1)
    - Birthday celebrations. 75th, 1988 (Box-folder 112/2)
    - Birthday celebrations. 80th, 1993 (Box-folder 112/3-4)
    - Cello Congress, 1984 (Box-folder 112/5)
    - Copland tributes, 1980, 1985 (Box-folder 112/6)
    - Cresta Blanca radio broadcasts, 1983 (Box-folder 112/7)
    - England and Belgium conducting tour, 1966 (Box-folder 112/8)
    - Grammy Awards, 1979 (Box-folder 112/9)
    - Hilversum, Holland, 1972 (Box-folder 112/10)
    - History of the Juilliard School, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 112/11)
    - Honors and awards, 1954, 1973-1985 (Box-folder 112/12)
    - Itineraries, 1943, 1972-1975, 1983, undated (Box-folder 112/13)
    - Jerome Robbins project, 1988 (Box-folder 112/14)
    - Kennedy Center Honors, 1988, 1994 (Box-folder 113/1)
    - Morton Gould Fund for American Music, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 113/2)
    - Murray Dranoff Two-Piano Competition, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 113/3)
    - Personal library inventory, 1969, undated (Box-folder 113/4)
    - Program outlines, 1941-1980, 1991 (Box-folder 113/5)
    - Pulitzer Prize, 1995 (Box-folder 113/6)
    - Radio broadcast lists and schedules, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 113/7-8)
    - Recording lists and schedules, 1968, 1992, undated (Box-folder 114/1-2)
    - Van Cliburn Piano Competition, 1993 (Box-folder 114/3-4)
    - Works lists, 1970s-1990s (Box-folder 114/5)
    - Works lists. G. Schirmer arrangements, 1983 (Box-folder 114/6-7)
    - Works lists. G Schirmer arrangements, 1991 (Box-folder 115/1-6)
    - Works lists. RCA Victor Records, 1959-1992 (Box-folder 116/1-2)
  - Musical Works Files, 1961-1995
    - Apple waltzes (Box-folder 116/3)
    - Bicentennial ballads (Box-folder 116/4)
    - Billion dollar baby (Box-folder 116/5)
    - Burchfield gallery (Box-folder 116/6)
    - Cheers (Box-folder 116/7)
    - Hosedown (Box-folder 116/8)
    - The jogger and the dinosaur (Box-folder 116/9)
    - Spirituals: for orchestra (Box-folder 116/10)
    - Suite for cello and piano (Box-folder 116/11)
    - Symphony for band (Box-folder 116/12)
- Writings, 1930s-1990s (Box 117, 147-148)
  - Articles about Gould, 1940-1995, undated (Box-folder 117/1-2)
  - Articles by Gould, 1962-1994, undated (Box-folder 117/3)
  - Clippings, 1930s-1990s, undated, Arranged by decade (Box 147-148)
  - Interviews, 1955, 1968-1992 (Box-folder 117/4-5)
  - Miscellany, undated, Lyric sheets and outline; Authors unidentified (Box-folder 117/6)
  - Program notes, 1944-1990, undated (Box-folder 117/7)
  - Scripts, 1942, 1991, Titles: This is war; An evening for Agnes (Box-folder 117/8)
  - Speeches, 1960, 1971, 1983, undated (Box-folder 117/9)
- Scrapbooks, 1919-1977 (Box 118-131)
  - 1919-1945 (Box 118)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 119)
  - 1944-1945 (Box 120)
  - 1945-1947 (Box 121)
  - 1945-1949 (Box 122)
  - 1947-1948 (Box 123)
  - 1956-1959 (Box 124)
  - 1959-1960 (Box 125)
  - 1961-1963 (Box 126)
  - 1963-1965 (Box 127)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 128)
  - 1966-1968 (Box 129)
  - 1968 (Box 130)
  - 1974, 1977 (Box 131)
- Photographs, 1920s-1995 (Box 132-133, 146)
  - Morton Gould, alone, 1938-1939, 1944, 3 black and white photographs (Box-folder 132/1)
  - Morton Gould, alone, 1962, 1983-1984, 1991-1995, 75 black and white photographs, 2 color photographs, negatives (Box-folder 132/2)
  - Morton Gould, alone, undated, 25 black and white photographs, 2 color photographs, 7 color slides, negatives (Box-folder 132/3-5, 146/2)
  - Morton Gould, with others, 1945, 1 black and white photograph (Box-folder 146/3)
  - Morton Gould, with others, 1950s, 2 black and white photographs (Box-folder 132/6)
  - Morton Gould, with others, 1969, 3 black and white photographs (Box-folder 132/7)
  - Morton Gould, with others, 1971-1978, 5 black and white photographs, 13 color photographs (Box-folder 132/8)
  - Morton Gould, with others, 1980-1983, 80 black and white photographs, 12 color photographs (Box-folder 132/9)
  - Morton Gould, with others, 1984, 5 black and white photographs, 6 color photographs (Box-folder 132/10)
  - Morton Gould, with others, 1986, 5 black and white photographs, 3 color photographs (Box-folder 132/11)
  - Morton Gould, with others, 1987, 1 black and white photograph, 7 color photographs (Box-folder 132/12)
  - Morton Gould, with others, 1988, 3 black and white photographs, 10 color photographs (Box-folder 132/13)
  - Morton Gould, with others, 1991-1995, 2 black and white photographs, 13 color photographs (Box-folder 132/14)
  - Morton Gould, with others, undated, 26 black and white photographs, 7 color photographs (Box-folder 132/15-16)
  - CIAM Congress, Warsaw, 1973, 7 black and white photographs (Box-folder 132/17)
  - Festival di George Gershwin, Venice, 1968, 37 black and white photographs (Box-folder 132/18)
  - Hosedown, Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra, 1995, 18 color photographs (Box-folder 132/19)
  - The jogger and the dinosaur, Pittsburgh Youth Orchestra, 1993, 17 black and white photographs, 6 color photographs, negatives (Box-folder 132/20)
  - Kaufman Center awards, 1995, 1 black and white photograph, 15 color photographs (Box-folder 133/1)
  - Miscellany, 1986, undated, 5 black and white photographs, 3 color photographs (Box-folder 133/2, 146/4)
  - Performances and rehearsals, 1970-1975, 1980s, undated, 17 black and white photographs, 16 color photographs (Box-folder 133/3)
  - Slideshow, circa 1920s-1990s, 59 black and white or color slides (Box-folder 133/4)
  - Steinway Hall exhibit, 1995, 10 black and white photographs (Box-folder 133/5)
  - Van Cliburn Piano Competition, 1993, 10 black and white photographs, 5 color photographs (Box-folder 133/6)
- Programs, 1935-1995 (Box 134-143)
  - 1935-1950 (Box-folder 134/1-19)
  - 1950-1958 (Box-folder 135/1-13)
  - 1960-1966 (Box-folder 136/1-11)
  - 1966-1970 (Box-folder 137/1-8)
  - 1970-1974 (Box-folder 138/1-8)
  - 1974-1980 (Box-folder 139/1-9)
  - 1980-1986 (Box-folder 140/1-9)
  - 1986-1990 (Box-folder 141/1-7)
  - 1990-1993 (Box-folder 142/1-7)
  - 1993-1995 (Box-folder 143/1-6)
  - Undated (Box-folder 143/7)
- Promotional Materials, 1930s-1995 (Box 144)
  - Miscellany, 1930s-1994 (Box-folder 144/1-3)
  - Newsletters and press releases, 1958, 1968-1995, undated (Box-folder 144/4-5)
  - Posters, 1971-1976, undated (Box-folder MAP A/7)
  - Recording releases, 1955, 1963-1964, 1970, undated (Box-folder 144/6)
- Financial and Legal Documents, 1942-1995 (Box 145)
  - Commissions, 1962, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 145/1)
  - Contracts, 1942-1996, undated (Box-folder 145/2-3)
  - Gould family name change, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 145/4)
  - Last will and testament, 1968 (Box-folder 145/5)
  - Miscellany, 1953-1964, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 145/6)
  - World War I, 1964, Chiefly production expenses (Box-folder 145/7)
- Artwork, 1982 (Box 146)
  - Morton Gould portrait, 1982, Oil pastel drawing by Peter Brock (Box-folder 146/5)